Guide to the William Rose Benét Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1895-1957; Series III; 16.34; 18 boxes + 3 broadside folders
  - Writings of Others
    - McCullough, Trudi
      - "I Am an Incurable Optimist," essay, proof, [?] August 2 (Box 128 (Broadside))
    - McKnight, Floyd
      - "Christmas Beside the Abyss," pamphlet, undated (Box 83, Folder 2849)
      - "This Christmas," printed card, inscribed and signed, 1942 (Box 83, Folder 2850)
    - Mizener, Arthur
      - "The Pulitzer Prizes," essay, reprint, 1957 (Box 83, Folder 2851)
    - Montague, William Pepperell
      - "Does the Universe Have a Mind?" essay, printed version, Saturday Review, 1947 September 6 (Box 83, Folder 2852)
    - Morley, Christopher
      - [Poems], drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, some signed, 1947, undated (Box 83, Folder 2853)
    - Mullins, Helene
      - "This Freedom," poem, typescript carbon, undated (Box 83, Folder 2854)
    - Nash, Ogden
      - "Lament on the Eve of Parting," [copy?], typescript, annotated, undated (Box 83, Folder 2855)
    - Nelson, Starr
      - "In the Boulder on the Shore…" article, printed version, Official Bulletin (2 copies), 1951 March (Box 83, Folder 2856)
    - Newbolt, Henry [John, Sir?]
      - "Nobis cum Pereant," poem, printed version, undated (Box 83, Folder 2857)
    - Norden, Heinz
      - Die Hellen Nächt, review, draft, typescript, circa 1942 (Box 83, Folder 2858)
    - Norris, Kathleen
      - "The Mirror Prisoner, or, What Was the Curse," booklet, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 83, Folder 2859)
    - Opalov, [Nicholas?]
      - "William Rose Benét: On Contemporary American Poetry," essay, draft, typescript, inscribed, 1942 (Box 83, Folder 2860)
    - Overton, Grant M. (Grant Martin)
      - Katherine Brush: Young Woman of Manhattan, essay, printed version, 1929 (Box 83, Folder 2861)
    - [Peirce, Waldo?]
      - Untitled poem, autograph manuscript, 1926 November 10 (Box 83, Folder 2862)
    - Phelps, William Lyon
      - "Stephen Vincent Benet," essay, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 83, Folder 2863)
    - Powys, Littleton
      - "Sang and Soared Away," letter to the editor, printed version, 1947 June 27 (Box 116 (Oversize), Folder 3359)
    - Reese, Lizette Woodworth
      - "The Upper Chamber," poem, typescript, corrected and signed, undated (Box 83, Folder 2864)
    - Ridge, Lola
      - [Poems], drafts, typescript, corrected, and autograph manuscript, 1920, undated (Box 83, Folder 2865)
    - Robinson, Henry Morton
      - "Mr. Beadle's Books," essay, printed version, The Bookman, 1929 March (Box 83, Folder 2866)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel
      - "Words and Images," essay, printed version, The New Republic, undated (Box 83, Folder 2867)
    - Salomon, Isidore Lawrence
      - "Birdsong for Rain, poem, typescript, 1948 August 7 (Box 83, Folder 2868)
      - "Poems of Affirmation," reviews, printed version, Voices, undated (Box 83, Folder 2869)
    - Sanford, George Alden
      - "A Vacation in a Fifteenth Century English Manor House," essay, printed version, National Geographic, undated (Box 83, Folder 2870)
    - Sarton, May
      - "Navigator," poem, [copy?], typescript, undated (Box 83, Folder 2871)
      - "New Year Poem, 1948," printed version, signed, circa 1948 (Box 83, Folder 2872)
    - Scollard, Clinton
      - "The Gulls," poem, typescript, undated (Box 83, Folder 2873)
    - Senex
      - Jonathan To Cal, printed version, 1925 (Box 83, Folder 2874)
    - Sergeant, Elizabeth Shepley
      - "Elinor Wylie: Intricate and Crystal," essay, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 83, Folder 2875)
    - Shelton, Julia Baggette
      - The Blue Mirror, printed version, 1945 (Box 83, Folder 2876)
    - Smith, Granville Paul
      - [Poems], drafts, typescript carbon, undated (Box 83, Folder 2877)
    - Smith, Harrison
      - Untitled poem, printed version, undated (Box 83, Folder 2878)
    - Spencer, Lilian White
      - [Poems], typescript carbon, undated (Box 83, Folder 2879)
    - Spencer, Theodore
      - "Psychomachia," poem, printed version, The Hound Horn, undated (Box 83, Folder 2880)
    - Speyer, Leonora
      - [Poems], drafts, typescript, and printed verson, undated (Box 83, Folder 2881)
    - Stimson, Henry L. (Henry Lewis)
      - "The Decision to Use the Atomic Bomb," essay, printed version, Harper's Magazine, 1947 February (Box 83, Folder 2882)
    - Storm, Hugo
      - "Beauregard," poem, printed version, The California Milk News, annotated by Elsa Gidlow, 1943 December 31 (Box 83, Folder 2883)
    - Swift, Ivan
      - "City Pigeons," poem, typescript carbon, annotated, undated (Box 83, Folder 2884)
      - "In Defense of Kipling," notes, autograph manuscript, corrected, 1939 February 22 (Box 83, Folder 2885)
    - Symonds, John Addington
      - "The Philosophic Flight," poem, copy, undated (Box 83, Folder 2886)
    - Taggard, Genevieve
      - "Try Topic," typescript, with printer's annotations, undated (Box 83, Folder 2887)
    - Teasdale, Sara
      - "August Night," poem, printed version, undated (Box 83, Folder 2888)
    - Thoma, Richard
      - [Poems], drafts, typescript and autograph manuscript, undated (Box 83, Folder 2889)
    - Torrence, Ridgley
      - "Lincoln's Dream," poem, printed version, The New Republic, 1941 [Febr?]uary 10 (Box 83, Folder 2890)
    - Troubetzkoy, Ulrich
      - "A Tree for Christmas," poem, reprint, inscribed, 1948 December (Box 83, Folder 2891)
    - Upson, Arthur
      - Untitled poem, copy in hand of William Rose Benét, undated (Box 116 (Oversize), Folder 3360)
    - Viereck, Peter
      - "My Kind of Poetry," essay, printed version, Saturday Review, 1949 August 27 (Box 83, Folder 2892)
      - "Parnassus Divided," essay, printed version, Atlantic Monthly, 1949 October (Box 83, Folder 2893)
    - Walbridge, Earle [Francis?]
      - "Poetry of the Supernatural," bibliography, printed version, 1919 (Box 83, Folder 2894)
      - "The Problem of Dr. Watson's Children," essay, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 83, Folder 2895)
      - "The Summer Pool," poem, typescript, corrected and signed, [?] February 14 (Box 83, Folder 2896)
    - Welles, Winifred
      - "Paean for February 3rd," poem, autograph manuscript (Box 83, Folder 2897)
    - Wilson, Edmund
      - [Poems], autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 83, Folder 2898)
    - Wilstach, John
      - "There You Are," poem, typescript carbon, undated (Box 83, Folder 2899)
    - Wood, Clement
      - "Four Women as Poets," review, typescript carbon, undated (Box 83, Folder 2900)
    - Woodworth, Samuel
      - "The Pride and the Valley," poem, typescript copy, undated (Box 83, Folder 2901)
    - Wylie, Elinor
      - "On a Singing Girl," poem, copy, typescript, undated (Box 83, Folder 2902)
      - "The Reading Years," article, printed version, Wings, undated (Box 83, Folder 2903)
      - Untitled interview, draft, typescript, undated (Box 83, Folder 2904)
    - Yeats, W. B. (William Butler)
      - "The New Faces," copy (incomplete), typescript, undated (Box 83, Folder 2905)
    - Zheleznov, M.
      - "William Rose Benét," essay, [transcription?], typescript, corrected, 1942 (Box 83, Folder 2906)
    - Others and unidentified
      - Miscellaneous writings, 1915-1950, undated (Box 83, Folder 2907-2911)
      - "Prayer for a World at War", undated (Box 129 (Broadside))
- Printed Appearances of Writings by William Rose Benét, 1904-1950; Series IV; 3.75; 6 boxes
  Organized into three subseries: Individual Titles (In Periodicals), Clippings, and Other. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically by title or supplied heading.
  Series IV. Printed Appearances of Writings by William Rose Benét includes clippings of individual works, full issues of periodicals containing work(s) by Benét, and other printed versions of works.
  There are examples of early work by Benét, written as an undergraduate while at Yale College, but most of the work found here includes short forms published in American magazines and newspapers from the early 1930s until 1950. Types of work include poems, book reviews, articles and essays, and short stories.
  Benét served as an editor at the Saturday Review from 1923 until his death in 1950, and the series includes long runs of clippings from columns that appeared in the journal. The two columns, "The Phoenix Nest" and "Round About Parnassus," include poems and discussion of literary and other topics. Usually attributed directly to Benét, the "The Phoenix Nest" is sometimes attributed to "The Phoenician."
  - Individual Titles (in Periodicals)
    - "Address to Archeus," poem, The Christian Century (9 copies), 1950 March 8 (Box 84, Folder 2912-2913)
    - Envelope removed from "Address to Archeus," poem, The Christian Century (9 copies), undated (Box 117 (Oversize), Folder 3361)
    - "Address to Archeus," poem, Fellowship In Prayer (2 copies), 1950 (Box 84, Folder 2914)
    - "And the Truth Shall Make Them Free," essay, National Parent-Teacher, 1942 October (Box 84, Folder 2915)
    - "Aristeas Relates His Youth," poem, The Lyric, 1918 (Box 84, Folder 2916)
    - "Ballad of the Blunderbuss," poem, Adventure (2 copies), 1933 November (Box 84, Folder 2917-2918)
    - "The Ballad of Resurrection Bar," poem, The American Scholar, 1933 January (Box 84, Folder 2919)
    - "But Once a Year," story, The Golden Book Magazine (2 copies), 1929 December (Box 84, Folder 2920-2921)
    - "Dark Legend," poem, The Lyric, 1933 (Box 84, Folder 2922)
    - "Day of Deliverance," poem, The Phiadelphia Inquirer, 1942 October 22 (Box 117 (Oversize), Folder 3362)
    - "The Exclusive Club," poem, The University Review, 1945 (Box 84, Folder 2923)
    - "Excursions of a Movie-Goer," essay, Films in Review, 1950 April (Box 84, Folder 2924)
    - "The Falconer of God," poem, The Golden Book Magazine, 1931 February (Box 84, Folder 2925)
    - "Five Hundreds Years of English Prose," illustration, Woman's Day, 1944 December (Box 84, Folder 2926)
    - Empty folder (Box 84, Folder 2927)
    - "Frémont's Cinnamon Steeds," story, Adventure, 1942 July (Box 85, Folder 2928)
    - "Godsend," poem, The Poetry Chap-Book, inscribed and initialed, 1948 September (Box 85, Folder 2929)
    - "The Hard Way Home," poem, Senior Scholastic, 1944 April (Box 85, Folder 2930)
    - "The Honor Role in English Poetry," illustration, Woman's Day (3 copies), 1945 March (Box 85, Folder 2931)
    - "Introduction," Northampton Poets, 1948 (Box 85, Folder 2932)
    - "Liberty Day," poem, The NEA Service (5 copies), 1942 (Box 85, Folder 2933)
    - "Louis," tribute, Demcourier, 1939 (Box 85, Folder 2934)
    - "Man from Maine: An Evaluation of the Latest Poet To Win the Pulitzer Prize," essay, The English Journal (2 copies), 1936 September (Box 85, Folder 2935)
    - "Men of the Hurricane," poem, Adventure, 1944 February (Box 85, Folder 2936)
    - "Michelangelo in the Fish-Market," poem, Contemporary Verse, 1916 January (Box 85, Folder 2937)
    - "My Brother Steve," essay, Saturday Review of Literature, 1941 November 5 (Box 85, Folder 2938)
    - ["A new world waits us…"], poem, Britain, 1943 December (Box 85, Folder 2939)
    - "Piscatorial," poem, The Yale Courant, 1905 May 22 (Box 85, Folder 2940)
    - "Poems," The University Review, 1950 (Box 85, Folder 2941)
    - [Poems], Saturday Review (6 copies), 1950 May 20 (Box 85, Folder 2942-2944)
    - "Poetry of the Sea," essay, The Lookout, 1945 June (Box 85, Folder 2945)
    - "Selected Poems" from Golden Fleece, Fiction Parade, 1937 January (Box 85, Folder 2946)
    - "Steeplechase," poem, The Lyric, 1917 August (Box 85, Folder 2947)
    - "Summa," poem, The Christian Leader, 1950 January (Box 85, Folder 2948)
    - "Thieves in the Night," Canadian Poetry Magazine, 1949 (Box 85, Folder 2949)
    - "Tribute To Jo Davidson," address, The Independent, 1945 October (Box 85, Folder 2950)
  - Clippings
    - Articles and essays, 1926–1948 (Box 86, Folder 2951-2952)
    - Articles and essays, 1926-1934, undated (Box 117 (Oversize), Folder 3363)
    - Book reviews, 1922-1948, undated (Box 86, Folder 2953-2954)
    - Book reviews, 1927 August 27 (Box 117 (Oversize), Folder 3364)
    - Open letters, 1928-1950, undated (Box 86, Folder 2955)
    - The Phoenix Nest, 1925-1950, undated (Box 86, Folder 2956-2961)
    - The Phoenix Nest, 1927; 1929 (Box 117 (Oversize), Folder 3365)
    - The Phoenix Nest, 1948-1950, undated (Box 87, Folder 2962-2965)
    - Poems, 1905-1950, undated (Box 87, Folder 2966-2972)
    - Poems, 1930-1946, undated (Box 117 (Oversize), Folder 3366)
    - Poems, 1905-1950, undated (Box 88, Folder 2973-2974)
    - "Qwertyuiop", 1926–1928 (Box 117 (Oversize), Folder 3367)
    - Round About Parnassus, 1929-1933, undated (Box 88, Folder 2975-2979)
    - Round About Parnassus, 1930; 1932 (Box 117 (Oversize), Folder 3368)
    - Stories, 1904-1934, undated (Box 88, Folder 2980)
    - Theatrical sketches, [circa 1904] (Box 88, Folder 2981)
  - Other
    - "After Seeing Desert Victory ," poem, reprint, [1944] (Box 88, Folder 2981a)
    - Poems on The Saturday Review envelopes, undated (Box 88, Folder 2982)
    - "Prayer for England," poem, reprint, 1940 (Box 88, Folder 2983)
    - Radio announcements, undated (Box 88, Folder 2984)
- Personal and Family Papers, 1847-1950; Series V; 18.76; 26 boxes + 2 art, 1 broadside folder
  Organized into seven subseries: Artwork, Clippings, Financial and Legal Records, Other Family Papers, Photographs, Printed Material, and Other Material. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically.
  Series V. Personal and Family Papers includes artwork, clippings, financial and legal records, photographs, and printed and other material. Artwork features drawings by William Rose Benét dating circa 1904 through the late 1940s. Artwork includes pencil and pen-and-ink sketches and illustrations for college magazines. There are also loose drawings and a sketchbook by Benét's friend, the artist Henry Martyn Hoyt, brother of his second wife Elinor Wylie, as well as a painting, "The End of the World," by Wylie.
  Clippings in this series concern William Rose Benét, Benét's literary work, family members, and other topics. Financial and legal records include publication-related records, such as contracts and royalty statements, and personal financial information. In addition, there is material relating to the estates of several family members. Photographs are subdivided for prints of William Rose Benét, his family, other people, and places.
  Finally, there is a variety of printed and other emphemera in the collection relating to Benét's personal life and professional activities. There are childhood school materials, calenders and diaries, a run of notebooks and manuscript notes, and scrapbooks.
  Additional material relating specifically to the estate of Elinor Wylie can be found in the correspondence file for the law firm of Coudert Brothers in Series I.
  - Artwork
    - Work by William Rose Benét
      - "Bartholomew Pendred or the Two-Fingered Hand," drawings, undated (Box 89, Folder 2985)
      - "Kit Carson's Dream," painting (1980.452), [circa 1948] (Box 89, Folder 2986)
      - "Limericks of a Benicia Bunch," drawings, 1905 (Box 89, Folder 2987)
      - "Pertinent Parodies of a Summer," drawings, circa 1904 (Box 89, Folder 2988)
      - Timothy's Angels, drawings [by Constantin Alajalov?], undated (Box 118 (Oversize), Folder 3369)
      - Drawing of SVB in chair, framed (1980.453), undated (Box 89, Folder 2989)
      - Numbered drawings (1980.563.1-), 1905-1948, undated (Box 89, Folder 2990-2992)
      - Numbered drawings (1980.563.1-), undated (Box 118 (Oversize), Folder 3370-3373)
      - Unnumbered drawings, 1905-1945, undatred (Box 89, Folder 2993-2995)
      - Unnumbered drawings, undated (Box 118 (Oversize), Folder 3374)
    - Work by Others
      - Bagg, Ned
        - Drawing, undated (Box 89, Folder 2996)
      - Benét, James, 1914-
        - Drawings, undated (Box 89, Folder 2997)
      - Benét, Rachel
        - Drawings, undated (Box 89, Folder 2998)
      - Biddle, Gary
        - Watercolor, 1927 (Box 89, Folder 2999)
      - Coe, Lloyd
        - Drawing, undated (Box 89, Folder 3000)
      - Dawson, Frances Rosemary (Benét)
        - Drawing, undated (Box 89, Folder 3001)
      - [Day, Clarence?]
        - Drawing, undated (Box 89, Folder 3002)
      - Fisher, A. Hugh (Alfred Hugh)
        - Etchings, undated (Box 89, Folder 3002a)
      - Flack, Marjorie
        - Drawings, undated (Box 89, Folder 3003)
        - Drawings, undated (Box 118 (Oversize), Folder 3375)
      - Fry, Kathleen Anne (Benét)
        - Drawings, undated (Box 89, Folder 3004)
      - Hoyt, Henry Martyn
        - Drawings (1980.564.1, 5-19), 1920, undated (Box 89, Folder 3005)
        - Drawings (1980.564.2-4), [1905], undated (Box 118 (Oversize), Folder 3376)
        - Sketchbook (1980.565), [1907?] (Box 90, Folder 3006)
      - MacKenney, Sally
        - Drawing of William Rose Benét, 1934 April 3 (Box 118 (Oversize), Folder 3377)
      - Marsh, Louise
        - Drawing, undated (Box 90, Folder 3007)
      - Morley, Christopher
        - Drawing, 1927 June 17 (Box 90, Folder 3008)
      - Opffer, Ivan
        - Charcoal portrait of William Rose Benét, [1920?] (Box 118 (Oversize), Folder 3378)
      - Walthouben, Herman
        - Death mask of William Rose Benet, 1950 (Box 134 (Art))
      - Wilson, Edmund
        - Drawings, undated (Box 90, Folder 3009)
      - Wylie, Elinor
        - "The End of the World," painting, [1920s] (Box 118 (Oversize), Folder 3379)
        - "Sun Maiden," printing block, undated (Box 90, Folder 3010)
      - Unidentified
        - Bas relief portrait medallion of Elinor Wylie (1980.504), [1920s] (Box 90, Folder 3011)
        - Drawings, undated (Box 91, Folder 3012)
        - Drawings, 1948 October (Box 118 (Oversize), Folder 3380)
        - Halftone printing block with portrait of unidentified woman, undated (Box 91, Folder 3013)
        - Printing block for Benét bookplate (75), undated (Box 91, Folder 3014)
        - Printing block for Benét christmas card, undated (Box 91, Folder 3015)
        - Transparency of seaplane in unidentified location, undated (Box 92 (Art))
  - Clippings
    - Relating to William Rose Benét
      - Death, 1950 May (Box 93, Folder 3016-3018)
      - General interest and brief mentions, 1904-1950, undated (Box 93, Folder 3019-3025)
      - General interest and brief mentions, 1915-1950, undated (Box 119 (Oversize), Folder 3381)
      - Literary work (A - M), 1914-1948, undated (Box 94, Folder 3026-3029)
      - Literary work (A - M), 1939 May (Box 119 (Oversize), Folder 3382)
      - Literary work (N - Z), 1928-1951, undated (Box 94, Folder 3030-3032)
    - Family
      - Baxter, Lora, 1931-1938, undated (Box 94, Folder 3033)
      - Baxter, Lora, 1934 April 29 (Box 119 (Oversize), Folder 3383)
      - Benét, James, 1914-, 1927-1949, undated (Box 94, Folder 3034)
      - Benét, James Walker, 1928, undated (Box 94, Folder 3035)
      - Benét, Kathleen Anne, 1933-1939, undated (Box 94, Folder 3036)
      - Benét, Laura, 1930, undated (Box 94, Folder 3037)
      - Benét, Laurence Vincent, 1914-1948, undated (Box 94, Folder 3038)
      - Benét, Rachel, 1949 May 26 (Box 119 (Oversize), Folder 3384)
      - Benét, Rosemary, 1937, undated (Box 94, Folder 3039)
      - Benét, Stephanie, undated (Box 94, Folder 3040)
      - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1933-1948, undated (Box 95, Folder 3041-3042)
      - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1941-1943, undated (Box 119 (Oversize), Folder 3385)
      - Dawson, Frances Rosemary (Benét), undated (Box 95, Folder 3043)
      - Flack, Marjorie, 1940-1948, undated (Box 95, Folder 3044)
      - Hartigan, Margaret (Thompson), undated (Box 95, Folder 3045)
      - Hoyt, Nancy, undated (Box 95, Folder 3046)
      - Norris, Charles G. (Charles Gilman), 1945 July 26 (Box 95, Folder 3047)
      - Rose, William W., undated (Box 95, Folder 3048)
      - Wylie, Elinor, 1921-1935, undated (Box 95, Folder 3049-3050)
      - Wylie, Elinor, 1921-1947, undated (Box 119 (Oversize), Folder 3386)
    - Other Topics
      - Other topics, 1923-1955, undated (Box 95, Folder 3051-3054)
      - Other topics, 1906-1950, undated (Box 119 (Oversize), Folder 3387-3390)
  - Financial and Legal Records
    - Bank statements, 1926; 1928 (Box 120 (Oversize), Folder 3391)
    - Bills and receipts, 1905-1950, undated (Box 95, Folder 3055)
    - Cancelled checks, 1926–1928 (Box 95, Folder 3056)
    - Check stubs, 1942-1950, undated (Box 95, Folder 3057)
    - "Contents of Safe Deposit Box", [1940s?] (Box 95, Folder 3058)
    - Copyright documents, 1944; 1947 (Box 95, Folder 3059)
    - Court document dissolving marriage between Elinor Wylie and Horace Wylie, 1923 October 1 (Box 95, Folder 3060)
    - Income taxes, 1920–1948 (Box 95, Folder 3061)
    - Income taxes, 1921–1929 (Box 120 (Oversize), Folder 3392)
    - Insurance records, 1930 (Box 95, Folder 3062)
    - Lease agreements, 1922–1943 (Box 95, Folder 3063)
    - Lease agreements, 1933 (Box 120 (Oversize), Folder 3393)
    - Letter relating to estate of Philip Hichborn, 1936 December 10 (Box 96, Folder 3064)
    - Lists, 1946–1949 (Box 96, Folder 3065)
    - Material relating to estate of Elinor Wylie, [1931?], undated (Box 96, Folder 3066)
      Also stored in: Series I. Correspondence, Coudert Brothers, Box 10, folders 393-396
    - Material relating to estate of Laura Benét, 1900–1932 (Box 96, Folder 3067)
    - Statement removed from material relating to estate of Laura Benét, 1910 October (Box 120 (Oversize), Folder 3394)
    - Material relating to estate of Laurence Vincent Benét, 1947–1948 (Box 96, Folder 3068)
    - Material relating to estate of S. V. (Stephen Vincent) Benét, 1909; 1928 (Box 96, Folder 3069)
    - Material relating to Harold R. Peat, 1935-1941, undated (Box 96, Folder 3070-3071)
    - Material relating to New Canaan, Connecticut property, 1926-1927, undated (Box 96, Folder 3072)
    - Other real estate agreements, 1937-1943, undated (Box 96, Folder 3073)
    - Promisory notes, [1928?]-1933 (Box 96, Folder 3074)
    - Publishing agreements, 1922–1940 (Box 96, Folder 3075)
    - Royalty statements
      - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1926–1949 (Box 96, Folder 3076)
      - The Dial Press, 1946–1948 (Box 96, Folder 3077)
      - Dodd, Mead Company, 1947–1949 (Box 96, Folder 3078)
      - Doubleday, Doran Company, 1928–1944 (Box 96, Folder 3079)
      - George H. Doran Company, 1925; 1927 (Box 96, Folder 3080)
      - Harcourt, Brace Company, 1933–1949 (Box 96, Folder 3081)
      - Harold Ober Associates, 1940–1950 (Box 96, Folder 3082-3084)
      - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1946–1949 (Box 97, Folder 3085)
      - Macmillan Company, 1944 November 29 (Box 97, Folder 3086)
      - Oxford University Press, 1946–1948 (Box 97, Folder 3087)
      - Random House (Firm), 1946–1949 (Box 97, Folder 3088)
      - Rinehart Company, 1947 August 25 (Box 97, Folder 3089)
      - Row, Peterson, and Company, 1946 April 20 (Box 97, Folder 3090)
      - Thomas Y. Crowell Company, 1948 July 30 (Box 97, Folder 3091)
      - Yale University Press, 1915; 1933 (Box 97, Folder 3092)
  - Other Family Papers
    - Benét, Frances Rose
      - Inventory of property, 1934, undated (Box 97, Folder 3093)
      - Itinerary, 1930 May 28 (Box 97, Folder 3094)
      - Last will and testament, 1939 October (Box 97, Folder 3095)
    - Benét, James, 1914-
      - Page from scrapbook, 1917, undated (Box 120 (Oversize), Folder 3395)
      - School records and material, 1924-1931, undated (Box 97, Folder 3096-3097)
    - Benét, Laura
      - School records, 1903 June (Box 97, Folder 3098)
    - Benét, Pedro
      - Biographical information, undated (Box 97, Folder 3099)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent
      - Citation for honorary degree, 1940 June 17 (Box 97, Folder 3100)
      - Notebook pages, undated (Box 97, Folder 3101)